welcome to our weekly at this moment
board meeting where right now we are
going through the
foundational documents as outlined by
protocol.love
and working on them for together tech
itself
we did the vision a couple weeks ago
we're going to do the mission last week
but one of us wasn't available and then
two of us weren't available so we
postponed it till this week
so we are going to be looking at the
mission
uh as i stated right before you got uk
henley i'm a bit of
well not a bit my brain fog is rather
large at the moment this week so
i tried to order them in my head and it
was or read them through and order them
and it wasn't really working
but they all seem important which is
partly why
it's hard to order and like whether
they're important for
game b or together tech
or time wise right now right like how
many of these are things that we can
actually implement right now and how
many and i don't know whether that
is part of it but like that for me is
was part of processing what was most
important and least important was like
wait is it for me
is it for game b is it for together tech
is it for
you know like there's things that i
think are a high priority but aren't
necessarily
together tech's current priorities so
anyway that was just a bit of my
going through maybe that might be the
place to start i had kind of the same
vibe as i kept going through it and i
kept sort of
getting stuck in the same areas and i
think just a bit about how the
conversation
last time went we're we're kind of like
i think crossing wires a bit
and not explicitly saying like okay
here's where i think we should end up
versus here's what i think our next
steps are because i think our next steps
are almost
never going to be ideal in like the
long-term scheme of things
but if the goal is like to get it off
the ground
i think that's where like you've got
your goals where those will never change
and then you've got the actual like
steps or tactics that you you plan to
to take to get you there and i think the
short term
there's going to be a lot of imperfect
ideas and solutions to get us to where
we want to end up and so i think it's
important
as we're talking through it to figure
out which part we're talking about
like oh i think long term we we'd want
to do x or we we
we want it to serve x roll and then it
might be okay
to get it off the ground we need to do a
certain thing
also i just wanted to reread the um the
vision statement we did decide on
because that will be very tied to it
right is like
is our mission going towards that which
i think will be the priority
anyway for me anyway helpful priority
prioritizing the missions
a vision a world where abundant
resources are available
to pro omni win projects
yeah so the the mission supports that
right
so um
so maybe we should just talk through a
few because i think when you're doing a
mission
it shouldn't be
like the vision it should be not it
should be not tied to time
so i think if we're having trouble where
things are like oh when are we doing
this then i think that those aren't
mission
those are strategy um
and i'm trying to pull up the document
to see but my computer is really slow
i don't know if someone else wants to
pull it up and share
that i can even do even with my broken
thing
because i can copy
if i copy that's the problem not the
base and i copies urls pretty
pretty easily um
[Music]
it's doing it from here to there that's
the problem i'm not from
from there to here
i think also also in the um in here i
think i had do have permission to change
it so i can just change it but there's
something that says vip
in order values improvement revenue
oh i think that's why that makes so much
more sense because i think we were
talking about changing it from profit to
revenue i'm like
that's not what that stands for that'll
be rbir that's enormous that makes sense
now
i remember the conversation
mvp and be happy
so do i need to share it then
i already shared it in the private chat
yeah oh no i meant
shared on the screen so our audience can
see what we're
reading but we don't have to that would
be a better
that part
url i did was very very long i don't
know if i want to be able to type that
out and do that but
no no i can i can do that
let me
so yeah like you said that's our vision
so these were the
sus suggested um
the brainstorming of the mission
statements not really suggestions
um so
actually i'm trying i don't have a great
definition of mission statement off top
of my head
um
so like local communities that is
something that
that that's a vision not a mission
i mean the mission could be build local
communities
um i think mission or action statements
um
[Music]
the first one seems to be rather
i mean yeah so i i really kind of like
that
unless that's missing something or
is too expansive or so what do y'all
think
yeah let's just read through the other
ones and see if there's anything that's
missing from there because i think
you're right i think that's probably
the full picture of it profit being
important but not number one
i'm wondering because i know the next
part down where we look at the currency
and how do we know if we're meeting the
mission
um not to get ahead of ourselves but
whether because i think the part about
the vip even though it's now wrong
is like that it's in order that it's
like the values
improvement profit so like it's like
first
is this i actually don't even know what
that means
improvement is like are we approved
improving the the
improvements like um
progress over perfection so like even
you know if
like if there's a bit a give and take as
long as it's towards going you know
a a net overall win for the values then
yeah
that that that's fine but sort of that
values are always number one
trying to improve those values you know
which is sort of like okay that's done
in context of the values
and then as long as n neither of those
is ever
um broken or violated
then you know the goal is to to make
profit
but just never at the expense of the
values or
or progress yeah and then
profit or money that is generated is
like yeah
yeah after gone back and think about it
and i still think the profit is the
correct word because you also want to
keep your expenses low just like a
company would
where the the difference being that is
profit that you then spend so it becomes
an expense
but it's sort of like the i guess the
two level there's the
absolute expenses like your staff costs
and hosting and
just you know all that stuff and then
the money that's left over you can spend
on other stuff on other projects on
i think that for me reading the mission
sorry the vision statement a world where
abundant resources are available to pro
omni win projects i really like the
first part of the mission because it is
like abundant resources and then we have
listed out the resources right
the knowledge the digital tools the
mentoring um
and i think the rest can probably be not
there then just that first part
my only issue with the four is that
mentoring is a very specific
thing like what we do for round tables
isn't really mentoring it's like
peer-to-peer right it's not someone
who's an expert
and so mentoring slash not that we don't
want mentoring that would be great but
we just don't have that in place but
there's also the like peer-to-peer
crowdsource
part of it that is
many minds that are not yet experts are
better than
one mind that's not an expert right i'm
also wondering how
different mentoring is from the
knowledge commons i guess the knowledge
commons is like a database and then the
mentoring is
as you said a one on one and so maybe
that's it that it's not mentoring it's
relationships it's like the relational
part of it
either as someone who's an expert or as
as
um on par or even your mentoring someone
else right you might be men in the same
conversation i might be mentoring you
and then you might be mentoring me
and just that part makes us peer-to-peer
right so there's something about
that the abundant resources are like
people information and infrastructure
yes oh and of course
resources money
yeah yeah i'm just wondering whether
those are specific enough
or um
it yeah because i mean people people
could mean
people to do the work and that's kind of
different from mentoring or
um and so yeah and i don't
like relationships that implies
i don't know better i'd say a
relationship not
not an exchange of value
you know you can have relationships that
that aren't
it's a it's orthogonal to you know
helping each other out
um so you think that maybe
is networking a better word it's a bit
of game a but it's this
it's sort of more in that direction i
think i mean well i mean networking
is generally the first step to the to
the mentoring or the giving feedback but
it's not that actual step
networking is finding people to do that
right um
uh but then i mean to your point
like one of the resources is knowledge
so that knowledge could be
either documented
or it could be people
um
[Music]
regardless of how the knowledge provided
and like in the early case we're
providing all that knowledge through
people because we don't have a database
so that's what kind of appear to peer in
for me so
um
but the yeah so but they're all
resources
so i mean to me knowledge is a resource
but
i don't know so maybe if we could
get a little bit more specific maybe
funding
funding knowledge and uh
see infrastructure kind of implies for a
lot of people implies
hardware and not software
don't um like assets or something super
vague
yeah i mean you could say
you know tools although tools still that
implies something you do something with
and not the actual thing
maybe there's no perfect word and we
just need to um
i mean i mean i like knowledge
[Music]
uh and then we could clarify the
knowledge to say that it is uh
commons and um pure
here that is what i meant by the relate
i maybe use the wrong word but
is there's information right which can
be cataloged can be databased could be
like if you're giving the same advice to
everyone you want in one location
but there's also no matter how
rich in information that is there's
still something else we offer that is
people
right that is like that there are people
here who also have projects and also
care like even if
like that is part of what we offer
whether it's mentoring or peer-to-peer
is like a community
the people even if you're not at a
relationship stage yet right like as
soon as you show up you're at a
relationship stage it's just like how
along how deep and how
yeah yeah i guess what i was thinking is
that the relationships
and just going through something
difficult with other people
is a separate value than the the
mentoring i mean they tend to happen at
the same time
or that knowledge um
abundant resources so yeah i think
pottery
uh-huh community is just kind of a
little i said camaraderie
oh yeah maybe we should just list
everything out
uh in in the many different ways to say
it and then we can
we can pick and pull so like
relationships
and we could just list them all actually
relationships i still like mentorship
because having someone come alongside
you that's been through it before
um you could still mentor each other um
uh camaraderie is what i said otherwise
if we're just brainstorming camaraderie
yeah
and peer-to-peer or i
wish there was a better name for it yeah
just well there is perigogy
which is the technical term for learning
from each other
okay
um what are some other learning new
words from my peers
right
i don't know if that's spelled properly
it's not um
what are some other uh uh
kind of like knowledge commons
hi maybe we should do you want to keep
it separate to different lines
like one is the people one is the
information and then one is that
infrastructure
and information overlap
yeah i mean i think we can break them
down once we kind of throw them out
there
such digital tools i really should put
these all in separate
and i guess they're just not going to be
perfect
uh what else and then actual
resources right like money but also
if you have something i can borrow that
is going to be um
okay like i use adrial stream yard right
like that's different
than borrowing it it's not costing him
anything but it is still helpful like
sharing in resources
that are um not necessarily money right
like money and the equivalents
money and things that save you money
funding and shared resources i think
that's
adequate
yeah so kind of a software is a shared
resource
um infrastructure would be a shared
and maybe digital tools is just another
way to say software but
i i kind of think that like
there's like somewhat of a difference
between um like
stream yard which is an outside one that
like if i had to have my own i'd have to
you know even pay separately versus if
we created it we're setting all of that
so like there's a difference
between internal and external and yeah
sharing in
the software fees and the digital fees
so that we can all share in them is
different than like what do we need and
then co-creating it together
or bringing it to the commons but
i don't think it needs to be included i
think just the end goal is to have
a useful pool of shared resources and if
there isn't something effective enough
then we may end up
building our own prism for some of those
but i think it still all goes towards
the shared resources shared tools
thing whether we build it or we're you
know buying it or losing it from
somebody else
yeah and so a world where abundant
resources are available to
prolong you in so i i kind of think
that if you were gonna like we could
literally just list all these things out
our mission is to provide blah blah blah
blah blah blah
and just list them all out um
i i think i think you could categorize a
lot of these under community
um and just clarify later like the
mentorship the camaraderie
paragogi and relationships
sorry um
um
[Music]
i'd still like to keep funding and money
separate from shared resources
even though technically that's a
resource just because it's very specific
and then i don't know where the
knowledge commons falls in
now interesting thing when we're talking
about community
it seems like there's two very different
sides to
that or i mean we might be helping to
blur those lines but um
or one are like the actual community of
people working on projects of you know
like actual possibly developers and
marketers and
and mentors there's that whole side of
things and then there's the community
like
users the people who are actually your
audience
um and i think it's mainly the first one
and then we're hoping for like a bit of
sort of
across a you know a project
cross-pollination
as things are happening but i'm i'm not
sure if we want to
well yeah i mean so this yeah this
community is specifically
the group of people working on it um
and i think the other one you were
saying could be called uh a user base
can user base go under shared resources
because that's a little bit like it's
not really i don't get to just like pass
off my users
but like it kind like it's
an audience yeah that's an audience
audience
although audience yeah audience
implies like it's weird
and it's not shared in quite the same
way right we're like
for me to share my stream yard i just
have to give her the the information
stream yard doesn't then have to make
its own choice but whereas for an
audience
all you're really doing is saying hey
check out these projects follow them if
you want to
but it i don't know it's the idea that
that event like we do have a pool of
users that are like together
text copy members right and so because
there's that pool
if if wikilection brings them in they're
you know i mean we're not
that beholden to together attack but
they're going to be more likely through
being in wikilection to be
somewhat loyal to whatever comes out
through that right and same with all
like that
whoever we bring on board is somewhat
being brought on board for all of them
if done in that way right and that is
part of the the power of
sharing in those resources voluntary you
know
sharing of a pool of people that
would be interested in multiple multiple
parts
leaving anything out
i think that's good it's just changing
them into mission like um
actiony things right like creating
relationships
i mean i i
kind of like that just being the heading
encouraging
the following resources
benefits for omni when
projects and ideas works
so i kind of like that as the heading
sentence for it
uh someone had posted posted on facebook
is one of the um
that the mission suggestion is increase
the adjacent possible question mark
i don't know if i like that for a
mission and i think we already have our
vision
but i do there's something there like
that is kind of the point right not
to create the adjacent possible always
does mean
that you're also increasing the then
possibility of the next adjacent
possible the next
impossible right like that's partly the
um oh where i think it was before
i think that's it i think that's a great
phrase and a great thing to do
i i don't think that that falls into the
category of a mission
agreed um
it's our mission's tangible like you
like you know when you've done it
do we know if we have a community so
yeah i mean that would be
that might be more strategy and stuff
like that
so i was just looking up the definition
on investopedia it says
a mission statement is used by a company
explained and simple and
concise turns its purpose for being but
that's our visions
well it is our purpose for being the
vision statement is what it'll look like
what that purpose
is fulfilled um
i should have thought about this let me
do
mission versus vision
i mean i think we're still going to have
to wordsmith and you know do some stuff
with these after we
we got the the basic foundations i think
really we're just trying to
define resources so that well we we
we may end up having a separate mission
for sort of each one of these
that all roll up to the overall vision
of increasing the resources available
for omni and projects
um which i think then you know will also
at some point have the
squirrel conversation with around omni
win but for now we're focusing on
resources
um well i i mean that's really i think
all we are if if this is
true once we get those two figured out
that's
that's most of it just the the resources
that we're trying to
help with and what projects we're hoping
to help with like that sort of those
two sides and then it's just you know
ironing it out so i think that this part
is still
quite important
yeah i yeah i mean i think this is it
it's just wording from here on out and
what level you want to go to in the
thing
um yeah i i agree
i think those are exactly what we are
doing
and so i keep trying to scroll on your
screen
i'm gonna gr i'm gonna gray these out
for now
so yeah so we could just
ford smith that or we could sit with it
for a while and wardsmith
i think partly i i looked ahead i
spoiler alert because
now we're going to be talking about how
we know if these are accomplished right
how do we know if the mission is being
accomplished and i think in doing that
we will be word smithing right like yeah
mentorship well how do we know if we
achieve it in figuring out our metrics
for achievement we will figure out how
to say it in the mission
if that makes sense right yeah
it's going to be kind of a feedback loop
or as we try to continue on we're going
to have to go back and
and wordsmith the mission and possibly
even the the vision a couple more times
to sort of
make it all a cohesive
thing yeah so i guess we could kind of
say
mission accomplished on designing the
mission because even though it's not
perfect it's
so there's that and i think the other
part is
um is
what was omni-win is it for saying
you know to provide resources to omni 1
projects
i guess one of the important elements is
when we say everyone wins who's everyone
likes something that might not be
obvious is you know the environment or
animals
yeah so
yeah i don't know where to put this and
possibly also
what does wind mean like
and again i don't think that we have to
get like super specific on
keyword smithing but just as we start to
have these lists of like okay what are
the resources that we're trying to
provide and who are we helping and what
do we
mean by help and i guess that's the same
as resources
um but just and this is i think
we're going to end up with these two or
three lists that we're going to keep
having to come back to
and massage and try to figure out how to
make them all work
together so
i have this um i started like a
very rough list where i mean it was just
like there's sort of
there's people which is a very broad
list where some of those are going to be
like actual staff and people working at
the company people who started etc
there's your customers um
[Music]
i mean there's a whole other spousal
group from your your suppliers to your
competitors
i don't think we're too worried about
our competitors also winning in this
case
um but you wouldn't want to be sort of
like overtly hostile
um customers suppliers competitors
and then also staff
um and then on the not people side
there's the environment which is a broad
term so i'm
definitely open to
alternatives there and then sort of in
the same vein but
slightly different is like animals so
things that are actually alive
and you know can feel pain and why not
but aren't people
it's like oh sentient being right yeah
so sort of like beings
and the world
maybe that's too broad the way i the way
i see it though the only reason that we
keep the environment up
is because it has secondary effects on
the being
true i think that that's great so air
quality
people need to breathe so if you're yeah
i think
that's true um
i feel like it's important to have the
other animals as one of the like the
the ecosystem itself is important like
the planet the environment but also that
there are other beings that have
emotions
and pain and culture and like all of
that
that also need to be taken into effect
and sentient life
is probably our more or more concern but
then even then it's hard to
define our octopus is sentient they seem
pretty sentient to me but they're not
vertebrates so we don't give them any
rights
there's this debate between sapiens and
sessions
and awareness versus conscious and
yeah uh consciousness and yeah all of
that
and in the body wow uh it is defined as
all sentient beings as like the totality
of
uh maybe not biosphere but uh
animals and entities that can feel
and um yeah can feel basically
that's it and you cannot uh ensure
that all sentient beings are well
if the environment is not well
so it's kind of implied that the
environment needs to be
stable at least unless of course we
define
well-being of certain beings as a
possibility to evolve
in interesting mutations
caused by changes in the environment but
i guess that's not
what we're talking about i think there
is
another the rest of the humans
we have staff but like if we're building
a factory there's mostly
all of humanity but also the local
humans right there's like the people who
are right
there but there's also like depending on
how how much impact you have
there's also just all of these things
right you if you live
next to a factory but you're not a
customer or staff or a supplier or a
competitor but like you still
live nearby and don't want to breathe
crap yeah
and i think that for me anyway omni win
like win so that's kind of the omni
that's the all
that the win part is like where were
they before
and where are they now right like if we
have this thing there did it improve
life for them right and for all of them
it might be it improves it in this way
but takes from
them in this way so it's like an overall
guys like our competitors are probably
going to be worse off that we're there
right except that they're all still
humans so they're like
you're gonna breathe clean air you get
switched out as well that seems
semantic like says less mantex but i
think it will actually be super
important
because you know there there's the whole
like how much free speech is to free
speech if you
are too open then you actually hurt
yourself like it ends up kind of being
the same thing like here's the areas
that we do and don't consider winning
and sort of things that play so our
competitors as humans yes
the the competing organizations that
maybe don't operate under these same
principles
go pound sand we don't care uh
our actual goal is to put you out of
business and hopefully employ all of
your employees
get gainfully and hopefully better than
you were and then
in that rain everyone wins
because i don't think corporations are
counted in in omni one it's
just about people and animals
and then what yeah what areas are we
looking at because like i
people care they have an emotional
attachment to their resources right
whether they're rich when they get their
yacht whether they
like that's not there's like a real
concern and not concern right i don't
care for costing our competitors a yacht
i do care if we're costing people food
clothing shelter right their basic needs
right
so it's like the perceived impact versus
the actual
if that makes sense so like i guess for
now it's called like improved
life stability or access to
needs maybe like improved access to
needs
does it give access to water okay does
it give access to cleaner water if they
had crappy water
before um and then like i think the
flip side of that is lessening harm
kind of the doing good and stopping
doing bad
um
one thing that i'm just going to put
here because i don't know how to put it
is just put long term wins
not short term so our future selves
the future humans the future animals um
because right if we're
taking someone's bus if we're if we're
if we have a competitor and they go out
of business
that maybe they're in their short term
disadvantage but the ultimate long-term
of the fact that
we're doing business in a way that
externally helps
them um uh
they're they're long the long term
they'll benefit from moving and
from an extractive job to uh right i
think that's a really
good point yeah like emphasis on overall
sort of long term
just because it does something good
today okay but what's that gonna do in
a year five years ten years if it's not
a long-term win then it's not actually a
win you're just you know
borrowing from the future to pay for
today
i think with this when short ones are
great but i think you're totally right
that long term is sort of the
the more important part
it also feels like in the um broader
world
they don't take like that that we need
the
gas and oil companies to stop it's like
okay but is there an alternative because
i still drive a car
isn't there like there's like the short
and long term for competitors for us
and meaning that i don't want our
business to necessary together tech
to go and dismantle other people's work
without giving a replacement right like
without there being an actual
like it's easier to to put all of our
externalities on the oil and gas
companies instead of on myself for
driving a car
right so it's like if i had an
alternative if i had an alternative fuel
source an
alternative way of transportation that
would be more short so yeah i don't know
why i'm adding all
this but long term i think is really
really important for improving life
access to basic needs
yes so um i mean to be an
omni when i'm i'm thinking through the
the phrasing to say
let me say it the long way it would be
like
if there are any it is any harm to
anyone than they're being any long-term
harm they're being compensated for that
um i see so like
it seems a bit like trying to improve
fairness or like if it can't be totally
fixed okay you're having this bad so
what can we do to help
do we give you something do we pay you
do we move you like yeah
yeah because i don't think that there's
a a requirement
that every action has to benefit
everyone
or equally benefit everyone right but in
the minimum
it should not harm anyone
but sometimes you can't even do that so
at least you can compensate
i i i like that which i think kind of
moves towards the like progress over
perfection
but like that being countered by okay
where there are going to be limits right
like if it improves for these
90 of people but like these 10 people
have to go into slavery
well no that's not
yeah i'm also how we had said before
that a win
is an improvement right an
improvement in any of these areas if you
just have it for life satisfaction
but for instance i know this is not our
realm but if we're big enough it might
be all around one day or someone might
wear like a ranch right a free-range
cattle ranch
is not kind to cows but it's kinder to
cows than what
what the other option is right so it's
like unless
if i'm eating meat i want to be able to
choose the nicer one even though it's
still passing externalities onto
the environment right it's just that
improvement on what is what is currently
being done
right so for the compensation i don't
think it's necessarily even just long
term
i think like even if it's a short-term
harm if you can compensate them you
probably still would
it might not be well if you have a guy
that you know
if if we put jeff bezos out of business
are we going to pay him
billions of dollars
i think we're saying that corporations
are immune from
right and so thus is unemployment
because otherwise
i'm saying yeah he's a human
right so that's where they're perceived
right like that thing of
employment in an organization and
continue profit we're saying that
like as long as you can meet your needs
no he he
is worth billions of dollars if we crash
his business he is no longer worth that
that's direct
to him right we're causing him
short-term harm
the question is are we obligated within
this framework to
compensate him i mean for him it's also
still kind of long-term harm because
you know if you crush the systems around
he's also never going to have that
that again but we're sort of trading
his long and short term for the long
term of everyone
yeah so i don't think trading i don't
think trading falls under
omni when trading one person for another
yeah and that is not trading right if my
like
if i say that i need to dominate people
and have 10 slaves and blah blah blah
blah like
i'm not actually being harmed by not
doing that i'm just like
i i wonder if it's almost like a ranking
like where improving life satisfaction
is great
but also kind of the last thing like if
we're lessening harm and doing long-term
good and you
you know giving more people access to
basic needs that all comes above
just making people happier
like it's still important so if if
someone yeah
he would be negatively impacted if we
took away if we created
an amazon alternative but he would be
negatively impacted from going from
being a billionaire to going to be
someone who has all of their needs and
wants met and doesn't have to worry
about someone coming in with a
guillotine
i think he would also be better off in
the long term but at the same time he
might not feel that way but the amount
of people who would be better off the
workers the customers
everyone else is like right but they're
nearly infinitely better off without
amazon
and his because his long-term um
cost to the planet not just the
environment but also that it's it is a
monopoly it is you know and growing
power and gaining stuff is like
what does it look like before our
alternative what does it look like after
alternative yes
we acknowledge jeff bezos is going to go
from rich to not rich
or really extremely rich to not so
to rich but not as you know neutron meat
um
from stupidity we're okay with that
because it's one person
and one person is like yeah
it was improved all of these people's
lives truly right we gave them actual
satisfaction
did his satisfaction go down the
multiples of the millions of people
satisfaction that went up right that's
not necessarily what we want to do
because that's just philosophy and like
you know like uh not philosophy you know
i'm whatever i'm trying to say the train
track and like
yeah you can't just make a decision on
how it's going to affect
dilemma happiness but um in this case i
feel like yeah we can because it's one
person
but also jeff bezos also gets long-term
benefits he might be rich he still has
to breathe he still has to eat food
yeah there's such a thing as imaginary
pain and
loss of a million dollars uh
i believe imaginary pain if you are not
talking about
uh loss of house or like shelter food
and everything
i just cannot uh imagine it's the same
thing as
harm being done to environment or to
like a living creature
causing physical pain and uh internal
dissatisfaction caused by
being poorer in terms of very uh
like um imaginary values like the dollar
kind of it's not the same thing so
so yeah one way to kind of say what i'm
hearing is
reduce someone's access to basic needs
if we're reducing your access to a yacht
as a
as an externality for what we're doing
we're not
we're not considering that harming you
right it's uh
it's go ahead oh sorry
uh i was just trying um i wanted to say
that
it's uh also exactly not the same thing
as uh taking something by force
or um we would be taking uh
his yacht by playing the same game
because
he's already playing so um
it's like part of the game this
possibility of
being um was upper apprehended
by some better technology or some better
way of uh
running a company so it's not even
a harm it's a direct consequence of
playing the same game
well yes but it's a game a
game you know i'm just saying that's
i think we're moving past that principle
when we say omni win
we're saying even even if they
put themselves in this thing we're not
going to
we're going to try to not have them be
harmed by it
um but just if it just depends on how we
define harm
right because even if even if
jeff bezos deserves it or even if
he if we shouldn't reduce him
past those basic needs right even if
that saves
i don't know if it saves another life we
have to have that whole discussion but
um which i think the basic needs part
because to me that's like okay well
let's say you are jeff bezos and you
have
i don't know how much this house is
worth i'm gonna say 100 million dollars
and we hurt him so badly he doesn't have
a house anymore because he
had to well come on you can get a house
you just can't have your 100 million
dollar house right so there's a very
different but like basic needs to me
i don't want to stay like everyone gets
the same wage across the board but if
there is that wage right which is around
60 000
that makes people happy how much is what
we're doing raising people to that line
versus the amount of people it's
dropping
as long as it's not below that line
sorry yeah your 10 million dollar house
is just not my heartbreak
you know like it's it's that yes we
drastically impacted one person but we
raised
this many people to to that level right
we doubled their income from 30 000 to
60 000 or whatever those metrics are
we gave people access to actual goods
that weren't
feeding off of all of the workers and
laborers all over the world
there's something about like a line that
is like is it
helping people up to that line and is it
dropping people below that line
it's like the true version of that
staying you know is it like
a rising tide carries all ships or or
something like that
there you go it's that but like the
actual version of that where we're
trying to adjust the water
some of that might you know if you had a
super high ship
i mean that's where the analogy kind of
falls apart where i guess some of it's
made from ice and we're taking them
well yeah like we're actually trying to
raise the baseline for everyone
we carry people that are under the level
but if you're over it and now people are
sort of getting closer to your level
we don't care about that
and if you dropped a bit are you below
the water no then we don't care
yeah it might be worth
writing up a framework that says here
are the things that we're going to try
and do
here are the things we're going to try
and not do accidentally or indirectly
and here are the things
that might happen but we don't really
care
so right so we want to get people up to
our first priority i think is trying to
get as many people as you can
up to that that uh satisfaction line
and if some people fall down we don't
care but we're not
we're not out to get them yeah we're
just that we're that's
game a playing its course and we're just
also playing a game over here
like if you're playing a game of soccer
and part of your roles is we need all
the balls in the area
and we want to play a game of of you
know
a football next to them if we have a
ball that now they don't own like and
that ruins their game
sorry but not sorry
and it's all all voluntary so
we are not forcing people to do anything
or to
experience a lot of a big house
it's all uh a consequence of
the environment of our mindsets as
human race just changing to value
different things than
are valued by game a so it's all fair
game to me
yeah i mean some of the concepts i think
of omni win would also say
or something i think people thought is
that it would be anything that
that has like no negative things like
you wouldn't even be
having a rich person have to lose their
yacht and
um but i guess we're saying we're not
shooting for that high
of the definition though
i would also add that um
there is um the
result of some uh economic systems and
some
dictatorship the consequence was
to uh
everyone down to a certain size of uh
not being very wealthy so to speak so
uh in like in russia or in poland
uh everyone was poor so it was kind of
equality
not everyone but most of the people
were equal but equal in poverty
what i'm thinking about here is
actively actually trying to
get everyone the possibility of having a
life like uh standard rich person
so it's not that we are going to take
all the yachts and burn them
it would be nice if everyone could get
and access at least
well access to whatever kind of
[Music]
pleasure experience they want for
example
if there's um if many people want to
have or at least go yachting for some
time
uh part of omniwin should would be to
actually make it happen or create
conditions under which people can
uh build themselves or something like
this
so we are trying to bring the standard
up
to uh the level of uh maybe not
jeff bezos but um like to reasonable
reasonably rich someone right
and i think that's where it gets weird
because it's not our goal to actively
reproduce others resources
but it will be a byproduct just because
of how game a works right like
every customer that we take away from
amazon is reducing the
the resources that amazon will
eventually have but
that's the nature of the game and not
our directly intended outcome
right i like that not actively trying to
reduce the resources or satisfaction
um although i'm still gonna constantly
in the group don't kick me out if i'm
like yeah we've got visa says wealth in
half
like it could still celebrate i can
still be part of it but they like to try
to bring it back to
what are we creating as opposed to what
are we destroying
even if i want to do both yeah and i
think it's just a better conversation to
have around
like hey look at how many people we
lifted above the satisfaction line as
opposed to
hey look at these three people that we
dragged down
like well who cares they're still above
the satisfaction line that's all we
actually care about
look at these ten thousand people that
we've set out way better story to tell
anyway
and i think just more effective i think
it's generally more effective to go
towards something than away from
something
i like it we have our what resources
meant what omni means and what wind
means
yeah yeah that's pretty epic
i was just thinking the other day i i
looked up the definition of omni-win in
uh
um the game b library and
it was not
i did not find any value in the
definition
it was it did not uh it did not provide
me any satisfaction
uh no one won in the definition of omni
wins
yeah and in honesty honestly i don't
know that
that what we defined here really fits
the ideal of omniwin
um but i think it's a good realistic
compromise and what we mean when we say
omni win in the context of
um together tech yeah and i think you
just brought up a good point where like
it
maybe isn't the ideal and this is at
least partially sort of like okay so
this is
i don't know what you call it the the
launch stage where we're we're still
deeply in a game a world and we have to
figure out how if it's there
as it gets more and more sort of clout
and more powerful as it starts to figure
out the
the best way to to play the games i
think well it's the clearer
defection will probably have to re
yeah redefine some terms
the expanding the adjacent possible
right or whatever we're doing we can't
just like
omni win ever like we can't do that of
course for what you're saying right
we're in game a world but like
constantly expanding what that possibly
looks like
um again and everything's voluntary so
we can't just
everyone's at this level we're not going
to tax all these people to move them to
this level because we don't have the
power to do that even if we wanted to
it's about creating voluntary things
that
increase everyone's standard of living
who wants to participate
and so doing happens to cost other
people their standard of living
but i do keep thinking what happens if
my
conservative and libertarian friends
would
watch this discussion their fear would
be
they would it would trigger them in
certain ways
that we definitely don't like
sovereignty
individual sovereignty which is very
very important to libertarians
is something that we hold dear and it's
above i mean
so i think one thing we need to do is
kind of list out our values
and then uh you know a lot of my
conservative friends have
concerns about i mean i i know several
of us in this group are very
anti-capitalism um
but i i don't know that our goal is to
extinguish that
but just put it in its proper place um
although i guess we haven't explicitly
discussed that so i could be
wrong on several people's opinions but
um my goal is
absolutely to dismantle capitalism but
yeah
so we haven't had that discussion that's
not like i
i like what you're saying because it is
we're talking about jeff bezos and i
don't think he's the problem it is
and no one's a problem but like the vast
majority of people who do see capitalism
as a positive and so hearing
i'm gonna dismantle it makes them think
they can never start a small business
right
it's all gonna go through the government
it's all gonna it's like no
well you just don't start a small
business in the same way it's like you
can find a group of people start a
project
own it until it's gone but you don't
yeah in an omni win world you're not
going to start it at coffee shop that's
for profit that like it just doesn't
make sense
it's based very much in gaming
you wouldn't be taking all the risk
yourself so i think it really is
painting a brand new picture that people
have never seen they've only seen
the capitalism picture and they've seen
the communism picture or like the
the socialism picture and that's the
only two realities that they've really
been
presented where it's like this
government that takes away your
sovereignty and runs things and you know
if they sort of work somewhat
efficiently it
can be good in areas and capitalism
where we have these giant for-profit
corporations
running everything and we've seen time
and time again that neither one works
but you'll get people need your reaction
to
oh you don't want giant corporations to
run things well the only other option is
a giant government i
don't want that yeah so i think it'd be
an interesting exercise for us to kind
of list out values
and even in a priority order if we can
because i think it'd be interesting i
think we would end up with still
individual sovereignty at and individual
responsibility which is important to
some of those
um groups is still pretty
pretty darn high on the list if not the
very top which
you know i'm an american and we think
individuality is
is the most important thing so i could
be i'm biased
by where i grew up but
uh yeah anyway so that might be an
interesting kind of next
step absolutely i was gonna just bring
in what radicand
reddick had said earlier of um
like the the perceived slight right like
thinking you're gonna lose a million
dollars
does isn't maybe the same point but i
think in this case it is it's how trump
got elected right like the perceived
loss of freedom the perceived loss of
potential in the future
is huge for people and
yes if they hear me say dismantle
capitalism that's all they hear is like
oh my god we're all gonna be standing in
long bread lines right which is like yep
that's history
but this is something new and different
and so like what does capitalism give
you
yes like freedom individuality
innovation yep all of that's here right
and so i think that yes values
so it's precisely the other way around
it's not
the capitalism gives freedom it's the
freedom
that makes capitalism work and that's
what makes
this precisely what makes it better and
what makes it win against uh socialism
for example
but yeah sorry but just people
do not see it that way because
again on purpose lack of education and
uh
too much of propaganda
yeah and and how much more innovation we
would have if if
we didn't have to struggle so hard to
meet our basic
needs every day um
you know put so much energy into that
which is a kind of a
necessary and is wasted um
that that could be fulfilled in another
way and that would give us the freedom
to innovate
i think a majority of human beings
if given nothing to do would strive to
make the world a better place
i think that's an inbred not even in
bread but that's a natural part of our
chemistry um and that has been something
that's been stifled
[Music]
i'm less concerned with the size of
albert einstein's brain
than the knowledge that like somebody
smarter than him has died
working in a sweatshop or a field yeah
right
right i think that is at its nature
one of the things that we're hoping to
solve here is well hey if we take all
these people and lift them all
because you can't sort of worry about
the you know
lofty ideals and those cut sort of grand
plans
if you're struggling below the water
line
yeah the main motto and message
and slogan is we need you as you
and not you as a lawyer or
like a worker or or you know anything
that you
could do we don't want you to do
anything like
special that we think uh you should be
doing
like pretty much everyone is doing uh
pretty much most of the people are
working to fulfill
someone else's dream right and
what we need is uh like you to be
you and that's the best use of
you that can possibly be yep
and i think we're right out of time so
maybe this is a good place to stop and
we can all kind of brainstorm on our own
about values and then sure
sounds good i was just looking up i
didn't realize you're out of time but
that makes no sense
um like quizzes that are for your values
would you like me to find one and we can
send it out and then you can like take
it and see
what your values are that's what i'm
going to be doing because i can never
remember what my values
are which one's first yeah if you run
across any of those
um probably good to share in the game b
projects group then everyone can see
them
yeah yeah might be good to just like
find i don't know five or so like fairly
quick quick ones just to see what the
outputs
are because i know that a lot of those
tests are garbage and also
you don't need it it's also a lot of the
values that the ranking you want we're
like yeah we don't care about
those values but they won't tell you
until you've done that
so yeah i think if we find a few of them
we can all sort of go through them and
figure out
which ones actually seem to work and
then
you just try to go through those as a
group after like figure out what is the
organization's value as opposed to each
individual one
yeah and i would i'd be thinking about
the organization's value if you haven't
done your own
then be sure and do that i'd i have two
or three lists some of my values
so i've done that exercise and and i
have it documented so
i'll just be kind of picking out which
ones work for the group and then
but yeah bring bring your brainstorming
and
we'll flush it out together
all right sounds good and yeah i think
this is an important exercise because
for me the values is like it doesn't
matter what our individual ones are it
is about maximizing
for all of them gives us maximization
for all of them like we only maximize
for one it's going to cost us all the
others whereas if we can hold different
ones
individually then we can maximize for
all of them
um but together tech should probably
have an order we're first this one
if it's not if this one's completely
negated we're not having the rest right
like it's it's doing that so
all right thank you
say everybody we're back tomorrow
morning for our round table
as per usual at the usual time